

36 E, Ambagaha Junction Road, Wellampitiya

🛘 (+94) 0719250289 | 🗷 sabiqsabry48@gmail.com | 🏕 sabiqsabry48.github.io | 🖸 sabiqsabry48 | 🗂 sabiqsabry48 | 💆 sabiqsabry48

"seek discomfort"

Summary _

Super nerd who loves Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Current Senior Web Developer at a start-up company called Tnaidar. 2+ years experience specializing in the front-end and back-end development and infrastructure automation. An experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the development design industry.

I want to focus towards the teaching career once I earn the title of Product Manager at the tech industry. It is a long way ahead to it but I hope to achieve to that extent in due time.

Skills

HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, Angular, React, NodeJS, ThreeJS, Python, Django, Tkinter, VueJS, EmberJS, Java,

Python, Flutter, React Native, Git, Github, Wordpress, Woo-commerce

Exposure: **MySQL**, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, TS, C++, C, Ajax, Ruby Other: **sweet Problem Solver**, Communication, Leadership

Work Experience

TnaidarRajamawatha, Mirihana

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER May. 2021 - current

- Defining site objectives by analyzing user requirements
- Design and develop user interfaces to Internet/intranet applications by setting expectations and features priorities throughout the development life cycle.
- Building sites for other startup e-commerce companies using React and Firebase as back-end.
- Learnt Woocomerce and am implementing it elsewhere on WordPress Sites.
- Managing the company's site and other client subdomains.

the Radiant.

Thimbirigasyaya, Colombo 05

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

HARDWARE ASSISTANT

Jan. 2021 - May. 2021

- Provisioned an easily manageable hybrid infrastructure (Amazon AWS + On-premise) to maintain order towards the whole company and orders.
- Built fully automated Invoice form and contract programs.
- · Designed an overall service architecture and pipeline of an Artificial Intelligence Program to be run on the site soon
- Implemented several API micro-services in Node.js towards client needs.
- · Deployed a centralized monitoring environment in regularity towards staff

UnigSolutions Borella, Colombo 08

• Implemented RESTful API server for car rental booking application(Gaman - which was later a failed approach) using PHP

- Implemented Kest full Art Server for car retrial booking approaching approaching a continuous tatel a latter a part of the Continuous and the co
- Built and deployed overall sample programs for POS systems made using C

Developed an easy-to-use employee status tracker using IOT technologies.

Clickbuy Dematagoda, Colombo 09

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

Jan. 2018 - current

March. 2018 - Sep. 2018

Aug. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Handled the business's online presence regularly.
- Implemented a platform to track customer orders.
- Currently working on the UI of the site.

MiTechSolutions

Bambalapitiya, Colombo 04

- · Evaluated interfaces between hardware and software
- · Advises customers regarding maintenance of software system

JULY 19, 2021 SABIQ SABRY · RÉSUMÉ

Kent InstituteWellampitiya, Colombo-Greater

TEACHER Jul. 2015 - current

- Conducted classes for Cambridge and National O-Level and A-Level Students on the IT and Computer Science stream.
- · Currently conducting online classes on Computer Science for both O-Level and A-Level students during the weekend.

Education

IIT(Institute of Information Technology)

Wellawatte, Colombo 06

Sep. 2018 - current

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Gone through Foundation.
- Completed basic Web Development front-end and back-end modules.
- Taking up electives in Quality Assurance.

HarvardX, edX Cambridge, Massachusetts

CS50X INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTER SCIENCE

2010

• Independent Study - Successfully completed the CS50 free online course provided by HarvardX

Wattala

2006 - 2016

LIS(Lyceum International School)

• Got through GCE O/L in 2016

• President, IT Society

Honors & Awards

2020	3rd Place , Datathon Competition Final	SLIIT, Malabe
2017	5th Place , Hackathon	SLIIT, Malabe
2013	2nd Place , Inter-school Presentation Competition Final	Lyceum, Wattala

Projects

2021	ONCO , an application built using Flutter infusing Machine Learning models for Cancer Treatment	https://git.io/JsEZD
2020	Amirah Gems, an E-commerce site for an upcoming jems and jewellery company called Amirah	amirahgems.com
2021	Danza De Ritmo, a site about an upcoming dance studio	danzaderitmo.lk
2020	MidWestEdu, a site for a college which includes online sign up register forms and such	midwestedu.lk
2020	Masjid Al Maqbool , a landing page made using React for a mosque in Sri Lanka which includes registration	maqbool.com
	forms for masjid events	
2019	Mabspace , a site that promotes an application developed for freelancers in Sri Lanka	
2019	Online Cart System (Store) - YOLO, a site which shows a simple customer purchase system using javascript	git.io/JJ0uB

July 19, 2021 Sabiq Sabry · Résumé 2